【家长提示】本片的评级为 TV-14-V，可能包含暴力等内容，
因而不建议 14 岁以下儿童独自观赏。
50年过去了
50 years have passed,
我的年岁却没有跟着增长
but I do not age.
时间  再无撼动我一丝一毫
Time has lost its effect on me.
折磨  却从未停止
Yet the suffering continues.
阿蛊的魔爪扼住了过去
Aku's grasp chokes the past,
现在  乃至未来
present, and future.
希望已然消逝
Hope is lost.
必须回去
Gotta get back,
回到过去
back to the past.
杰克武士
Samurai Jack.
Translated by @SerCom_KC
OPEN TRANSLATION PROJECT
Ohh!
翻译版本  v1.0.0-CHS
Ugh!
对不起  我不是嫌…
I'm so sorry. It's not --
翻译  SerCom_KC
对  我知道  不是因为我们刚才那个  是那个…
No, I know, not from the thing that we did, but --
是那个怪物的…
But it's the creature's...
…残留物太…
... the residue that is...
校对  SerCom_KC
嗯嗯  这里还有一点
Mm-hmm. There's still some left.
对对对  是的
Oh, right. Oh, yes.
啊  对了
Oh! Wait.
我还穿着你的长袍呢
I still have your robe.
是着！
Gi!
ぎ
你  你还是穿着吧
Y-You should still wear that.
呃  这里还是有点漏风的
Uh, it's very drafty in here.
我去找件衣服吧
I'm gonna find some clothes.
好啊  那就  等会儿在外面碰头？
Very well. I'll, uh, meet you outside, then?
嗯
Yes.
那  我就先去了
Well, I better go,
毕竟  你看  这地方漏风
'cause, you know, it's very drafty,
而且你也没穿什么衣服
and you're not wearing any clothes, either.
是呢
Yes.
那就  等会儿见啦
I'll see you in a bit, then.
拜
Bye.
我要上哪儿去找衣服啊
Where am I gonna find some clothes?
Hmm.
这样…也行吧
Well... this could work.
务必小心
Be careful.
我知道
I know.
这种感觉  以前从未有过
This... has never happened before.
你打算怎么办？
What are you going to do?
我不知道
I don't know.
阿喜
Ashi.
嗨
Hi.
收拾得挺干净的嘛
This all looks quite lovely.
谢谢夸奖
Thank you.
不用客气
You're welcome.
我们坐下来吧？
S-Should we sit?
嗯
Yes.
对了  我搞了点吃的
Oh, and I have food.
正巧  我也是
So do I.
感觉有点难嚼啊
A little chewy.
是啊
Yes.
啊  不过还是很好吃的
Oh, but still very good.
还来点吗？
More?
不了  谢谢
No, thank you.
杰克  你想家吗？
Jack, do you ever think about home?
每天都想
Every day.
我的家人  我的家乡  所有这一切
My family, my home -- all of it.
我的父亲是当时的君王
My father was the emperor,
所以我们住的宫殿可以看到整个村庄
so we lived in the palace overlooking the whole village.
那座宫殿很高  直插云霄
It was so high up in the air that it touched the clouds.
向外望去  就能欣赏到四季变换的美景
I would just stare out at the beauty of the seasons changing.
夏日照耀着山谷  拖出优美的长影
The summer sun blanketed the valley with long, beautiful shadows.
秋叶又会呈现出各种各样的颜色
The fall leaves brought a bounty of color.
冬季则是纯白一片
Winter was so white.
然后在灿烂的樱花之中迎来春季
And the cherry blossoms in the spring.
那个…有女孩子陪你吗？
And... was there a girl?
有啊  很多
Yes, many.
噢  等下
Oh! Wait.
我…你是指那个意思？
I -- You mean a girl?
没有  没有
No, no.
我8岁的时候…
I was only 8 when...
阿蛊就来了
Aku came.
之后就…
And then everything...
抱歉  杰克
Jack, I'm so sorry.
我不是有意…
I didn't mean to...
偶尔能回忆一下阿蛊来之前的事情也挺好
It is nice to remember the time before Aku.
毕竟那般光景  也只有通过回忆才看得到了
It is the only way I will ever see it again -- as a memory.
杰克？
Jack?
Jack?!
杰克
Jack.
Aha!
太好了  宝贝  我终于到了！
Yeah, baby! I really made it!
Whoo!
等等  啥玩意儿？
Wait. What's that up ahead?
阿蛊？
Aku?
这么热情的嘛
What a welcome!
阿蛊  宝贝  我回来了
Aku, baby, I'm back.
我无情懦夫回来啦！
Scaramouche has returned!
啥…
What the --
你好
Hello.
你听到的这个声音就是我  阿蛊！
You are now hearing the voice of Aku!
不幸的是  我已经不能再接受任何预约了
Unfortunately, I will no longer be available for any more appointments.
由此给你带来的不便  我深表遗憾
I'm sorry for any inconvenience this may have caused you.
现在  快滚！
Now, go!
这可不行  宝贝
Oh, no, baby.
累死累活地赶到这里才不是为了打退堂鼓
I did not come all this way for nothing.
好在我无情懦夫无所不知
Luckily, Scaramouche knows scarymuch
这里的口子我全知道  宝贝
about all the ins and outs, babe.
阿蛊！
Aku!
快滚啦
Go away.
没听见录音吗？
Didn't you hear the recording?
别来烦我！
Leave me alone!
别急  阿蛊蛊  我这儿有点小杰杰的消息
Oh, but, Aku-kachu, I got some info on Jack-o
绝对能让您大吃一惊  宝贝！
that's outta this world, babe!
Ugh.
啥？
Whaaaat?!
您就听着  待我慢慢讲
Feast your ears on this.
话说您老有耳朵吗？
I mean, do you even have ears?
那两个鹿角一样的东西听得到吗？
Like, can those antler things even hear?
讲重点！
Get on with it!
听着  老大  小杰杰把他的剑儿给丢了
Dig this, boss -- Jack-o has lost his sword-o.
当真？
Are you sure?!
千真万确  千真万确！
Yes! Yes!
我以我这条命起誓！
I'll bet my life on it!
甚喜！
What joy!
耶  我变回来了  宝贝！
Yeah! I'm back, baby!
Oh, yeah!
♪ Unh, unh, doo-doo-doo doo-doo ♪
♪ Doo-doo-doo-doo doo-doo-doo ♪
Oh, yeah!
我记得这个地方
I know this place.
※补番指南：第叁拾贰集（EPISODE XXXII: Jack and the Traveling Creatures）
杰克…为什么？
Jack... why?
为什么你一声不吭就走了
Why did you just leave like that?
你不该跟着我的
You shouldn't have followed me.
回去吧
You need to go back.
回去？
Go back?
不行
No.
我哪儿都不去
I'm not going anywhere.
你到底怎么了？
What's going on?
你不会明白的
You don't understand.
那就把它解释明白啊
So help me understand.
杰克
Jack.
这么多年来
All these years,
我目睹过太多无辜的人们受到阿蛊的迫害
I have seen so many innocents fall victim to Aku --
他们都是善良  正直的人
kind and decent people --
我的朋友  我的家人  无一例外
my friends, my family -- every one of them.
他的邪恶之力把我所有深爱之人…都带走了
His evil has taken everything I've ever... loved.
留给我的只剩下回忆
All I have left are memories.
我不想让你变成又一段回忆
I do not want you to become just a memory.
杰克  你想一想
Jack, don't you see?
我们的命运相互交织  把我们带到了这里
Everything that has happened in our lives has brought us here --
此时此刻  我们就在一起
right now, together.
让我们两个人一起打败阿蛊吧
And together, we're going to defeat Aku.
杰克武士！
Samurai Jack!
阿蛊！
Aku!
阿蛊
Aku?
这事儿拖得太久了  实在是太久了
It has been too long -- far, far too long.
你现在是不是在想
But you're probably saying to yourself,
“为什么？为什么突然又见面了？”
"Why? Why now for our sudden reunion?"
这个嘛  有只小鸟报告说…
Well, a little birdie told me...
杰克武士把全宇宙唯一一个
... that Samurai Jack has lost the one thing
能消灭阿蛊的东西给丢了！
in the entire universe that can destroy Aku!
你个大笨蛋！
You fooooooooooool!
Ugh?!
那个  吾主  我…
Oh, but, master, I --
啊  今天叙旧聊得真开心
Well, it has been nice catching up,
不过我要走了
but I should go.
我就不打扰你和你的女性朋友了
I don't want to interrupt you and your lady friend.
就当做我没来过吧
Pretend I was never here.
失陪了
I'll let myself out.
阿蛊！
Aku!
等等
Wait a minute.
我闻到了什么  好熟悉的味道啊
I smell something -- something very familiar.
我闻到了我的味道
I smell me!
疯言疯语！
Madness!
等等！暂停！
Hold it! Time out!
我是说真的
Really!
这里还有一个阿蛊  除了我以外
There's more Aku here, besides me.
不准过来！
Stay back!
没错
Yes.
她的体内有我的味道
I smell me inside of her.
阿喜
Ashi.
杰克
Jack.
怎么会有这种事呢？
But how can that be?
我从来都没…噢  等下
I never -- Oh, wait.
是有那么一次
There was that one time.
阿——蛊——
Aaaaaaaaakkkkkkkuuuuuuu.
不错嘛
Not bad.
阿——蛊——
Aaaaaaaaakkkkkkkuuuuuuu.
没错  确实是个精致的复制品
Yes, an attractive replica,
但它在原型面前一样会黯然失色
but it pales to the original.
来！
Here!
敬奉我吧  阿蛊之女
Worship me, daughters of Aku!
也就是说她把那东西…
So she must have...
喝掉了？
drank it?
然后就…
And then...
这就是你的真面目  阿蛊的亲生女儿
Here you are, a true daughter of Aku.
不！
No!
阿蛊！
Aku!
Oh?!
Yaaaagh!
Aaah!
阿喜？
Ashi?
我…这不是我的本意！
I-I didn't do this!
这就是你的本意
Yes, you did.
杰克！
Jack!
阿喜？
Ashi?
不是我啊！
It's not me!
怎么会不是呢  甜心
Of course it is, sweetheart.
你肯定不会让那个凶恶的老武士伤到你爹爹吧
You wouldn't let your daddy get hurt by that bad ol' Samurai.
杰克！
Jaaack!
我阻止不了！
I can't stop this!
我完全没法控制自己！
I can't control myself!
你要抵抗下去！
You must fight it!
抵抗住！
Fight!
Aah!
我已经在努力了！
I'm trying!
阿喜  注意力集中
Ashi, focus!
打破枷锁！
Break free!
我说  一个人努力把自己小孩养大带好
I mean, you try and raise them right,
结果小孩却跑去跟自己的死敌混了
then they run off with your mortal enemy.
作为一个当爹的  这种情况下还能做什么呢？
What's a dad to do?
杰克！
Jack!
完全没用啊！
Nothing is working!
不要屈服
Don't give in.
抵抗  阿喜
Fight, Ashi.
抵抗下去！
Fight it!
阿喜  你跟你父亲不一样
Ashi, you are not your father.
跟你母亲也不一样
You are not your mother.
你就是你自己
You are your own person.
你本性正直
You are good.
你可以从内心打败他的
You can defeat him from inside.
真是无聊
Boring!
甜心  你要拿出你最好的一面才能打败他
Sweetheart, you have to bring out your best to defeat him,
而你最好的一面  就是我！
and your best part is meeeee!
阿喜！
Ashi!
不要啊！
Noooooo!
阿喜！
Ashi!
阿喜
Ashi.
这才是我的乖女儿
That's my girl.
阿喜？
Ashi?
阿喜！
Ashi!
杰克！
Jack!
杀了我  杰克！
Kill me, Jack!
杀了我  然后消灭阿蛊！
Kill me, then destroy Aku!
阿喜！
Ashi!
只能这样了
You have to do it.
快点！
Do it now!
快杀了我！
Kill me!
我…做不到啊
I can't.
停！
Stooooooooooop!
♪ Watch out ♪
♪ Gotta get back ♪
♪ Back to the past ♪
♪ Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack ♪
♪ Samurai Jack ♪
♪ Wa-Watch out ♪
第壹佰集
♪ Gotta get back, back to the past, Samurai Jack ♪
♪ Watch out ♪
♪ Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack, Jack ♪
♪ Gotta get back ♪
♪ Samurai Jack ♪
♪ Wa-Watch out ♪